<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<about>
    <gb>The Game Boy is an 8-bit handheld game console which was developed and manufactured by Nintendo and first released in the 100th anniversary of Nintendo in Japan on April 21, 1989, in North America on July 31, 1989 and in Europe on September 28, 1990. It is the first handheld console in the Game Boy line and was created and published by Satoru Okada and Nintendo Research &amp; Development 1.This same team, led by Gunpei Yokoi at the time, is credited with designing the Game &amp; Watch series as well as several popular games for the Nintendo Entertainment System. The original internal codename for the Game Boy was "Dot Matrix Game", which its initials came to be featured on the final product's model number, "DMG-01". The internal reception of the device was initially very poor; the DMG even earned from Nintendo employees the derogatory nickname "DameGame", dame being the Japanese for "hopeless" or "lame" in that context.</gb>
    <gbc>The Game Boy Color (abbreviated as GBC) is a handheld game console manufactured by Nintendo, which was released on October 21, 1998 in Japan and was released in November of the same year in international markets. It is the successor of the Game Boy. The Game Boy Color features a color screen. It is slightly thicker and taller and features a slightly smaller screen than the Game Boy Pocket, its predecessor.The Game Boy and Game Boy Color combined have sold 118.69 million units worldwide making it the 3rd best selling system of all time.</gbc>
    <n64>The Nintendo 64 stylized as the NINTENDO^64 and abbreviated to N64, is Nintendo's third home video game console for the international market. Named for its 64-bit central processing unit, it was released in June 1996 in Japan, September 1996 in North America, March 1997 in Europe and Australia, September 1997 in France and December 1997 in Brazil. Codenamed "Project Reality", the N64 design was mostly complete by mid-1995, but its launch was delayed until 1996, when Time named it Machine of the Year. It sold 32.93 million units worldwide. The console was released in a range of colors and designs over its lifetime.</n64>
    <nes>The Nintendo Entertainment System (commonly abbreviated as NES) is an 8-bit home video game console that was developed and manufactured by Nintendo. It was initially released in Japan as the Family Computer (aka Famicom and abbreviated as FC) on July 15, 1983, and was later released in North America during 1985, in Europe during 1986 and 1987, and Australia in 1987. The code name for the project was "GameCom", but Masayuki Uemura's wife proposed the name "Famicom", arguing that "In Japan, 'pasokon' is used to mean a personal computer, but it is neither a home or personal computer. Perhaps we could say it is a family computer."</nes>
    <snes>The SNES is Nintendo's second home console, following the Nintendo Entertainment System (NES). The console introduced advanced graphics and sound capabilities compared with other systems at the time. The development of a variety of enhancement chips integrated in game cartridges helped to keep it competitive in the marketplace. The SNES was a global success, becoming the best-selling console of the 16-bit era despite its relatively late start and the intense competition it faced in North America and Europe from Sega's Genesis/Mega Drive console. The SNES remained popular well into the 32-bit era. It continues to be popular among collectors and retro gamers, some of whom still make homebrew ROM images and in Nintendo's emulated rereleases.</snes>
    <pc>The PC/DOS or MS-DOS was the revolution in gaming in the 90s. Many games were released on Floppy drives, including Prince of Persia, Skyroads, Chips Challenge.</pc>
</about>